Guide to the Charles W. Ranson Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Organizations Served, Series V
  - National Council of Churches of Christ -"Joint Program on World Justice and Development", 1969 (Box 14, Folder 197)
  - National Council of Churches of Christ, 1970-1971 (Box 14, Folder 198)
  - Princeton Theological Seminary, 1952 (Box 14, Folder 199)
  - Sigma Chi, 1966-1971 (Box 14, Folder 200)
  - Survey Application Trust, 1961-1963 (Box 14, Folder 201)
  - Theological Education Fund (TEF) - Original Proposal; See Also: RG 500 for TEF, 1957 (Box 14, Folder 202)
  - TEF, 1960-1967 (Box 14, Folder 203)
  - TEF - Mexico City Theological Community, 1966-1967 (Box 14, Folder 204)
  - Theological Education Fund (TEF), 1968-1970 (Box 15, Folder 205)
  - TEF, 1971-1976, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 206)
  - TEF - Serampore College, India, 1975-1976 (Box 15, Folder 207)
  - TEF - Notes, Sermons, etc., n.d. (Box 15, Folder 208)
  - Union Theological Seminary, Program of Advanced Religious Studies (PARS) - Board of Advisors, 1958-1963 (Box 15, Folder 209)
  - United Board for Christian Higher Education in Asia (UBCHEA), 1967-1972 (Box 15, Folder 210)
  - UBCHEA, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 211)
  - World Council of Churches - Second Assembly Evanston, Illinois, 1954 (Box 15, Folder 212)
  - World Council of Churches - Second Assembly Evanston, Illinois - continued, 1954 (Box 16, Folder 213-215)
  - World Council of Churches -"Annotated Agendas for the 3rd Assembly" New Delhi, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 216)
  - World Council of Churches - Meeting of Theological Educators, New Delhi, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 217)
  - World Council of Churches, 1948-197217 (Box 16, Folder 218)
- Biographical Documentation, Series VI
  - Curriculum Vitae, 1964, 1975, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 219)
  - Biographical Sketches, 1945-1964, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 220)
  - Photographs (Box 17, Folder 221)
  - Miscellaneous Awards and Citations (Box 17, Folder 222)
  - Family Deaths, 1947-1971 (Box 17, Folder 223)
  - Programs - Sermons and Addresses by Ranson, 1945-1977, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 224)
  - Programs - Services Attended (?), 1948-1957, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 225)
- Collected Material, Series VII
  - Printed/Typeset Material re. Organizations and Events: Association of Theological Schools in South East Asia; See: Yale Divinity School Library HR 097
  - Printed/Typeset Material re. Organizations and Events: British Conference of Christian Youth, 1951 (Box 18, Folder 226)
  - Printed/Typeset Material re. Organizations and Events: Church of South India; See: Yale Divinity School Library HR 501
  - Printed/Typeset Material re. Organizations and Events: International Council of Christian Churches, 1949-1955 (Box 18, Folder 227)
  - Printed/Typeset Material re. Organizations and Events: United Theological College, Bangalore; See: Yale Divinity School Library HR 500
  - Printed/Typeset Material re. Organizations and Events: International Training Institute for Asian Churchmen, Singapore, 1969 (Box 18, Folder 228)
  - Writings/Reports of Others re. Christianity in China:"A Manifesto on the Direction of the Work of Chinese Christianity From Now On" - Bishop Kiang, Dr. T.C. Chao, Y.T. Wu, Cora Deng, Y.C. Tu, H.H. Tsui, L.M. Liu, N.A. Ai, 1950 (Box 18, Folder 229)
  - Writings/Reports of Others re. Methodism:"A Wesleyan View of Reunion," - Rev. Franz Hildebrandt;"The Bases from Which a Methodist Christian Thinks: The Authority of Tradition and Experience," - A. Raymond George;"The Bases from Which a Methodist Christian Thinks: The Bible," - Owen E. Evans;"Reason and Religion Joined," - Bernard E. Jones; Notes and Addresses from Southern New England Conference (1970) (Box 18, Folder 230)
  - Writings/Reports of Others re. Missions, Ecumenism:"Address to Africa Committee," - Rev. D. Webster;"Report on Visit to Bangalore," - R.G. Cochrane;"Religion and Change," - Pferrer;"Mission After Vatican II: Problems and Positions," - Samuel Rayan;"Christ's Call to Unity and Mission," - E.F.Smith;"Unfaith and Other Faiths," - Rev. Lesslie Newbigin;"Aspirations of Contemporary Man,"- Dr. Donald G.S. M'Timkulu;"The World of the 60's," - Ernest A. Gross;"Christian Faith and Totalitarian Rule," - Dr. Will Herberg;"A Visit to New York," - John Lawrence;"The Kerygma, the Church, and the Ministry," R.W. Funk (Box 18, Folder 231)
  - Writings/Reports of Others re. Oxford English Dictionary:"The Making of a Dictionary," (Talk given by the son of the author of the Oxford Dictionary) (Box 18, Folder 232)
  - Writings/Reports of Others re. Theological Education:"Theological Education in India," - a report;"University College of Fort Hare;""By Die Fontein;""The University College of Rhodesia and Nyasaland;""Double Wrestle," - The Report on the Consultation on Theology and Theological Education in Indonesia;"Theological Education in the South Pacific Islands;""The Cultural and Vocational Aspects of Theological Education" (Box 18, Folder 233)
  - Writings/Reports of Others re. Misc. Quotes and Poems (Box 18, Folder 234)